<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2013s on code.zoia.org</title>
    <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2013s on code.zoia.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://code.zoia.org/2013/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cubr, a Rubik&#39;s cube solver written in Python</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/09/27/cubr-a-rubiks-cube-solver-written-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/09/27/cubr-a-rubiks-cube-solver-written-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Cubr is a program by Chris Baker. You mix up a Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube, show it to your computer&amp;rsquo;s webcam, and magically the cube begins to solve itself.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why virtual isn&#39;t real to your brain</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/06/04/why-virtual-isnt-real-to-your-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/06/04/why-virtual-isnt-real-to-your-brain/</guid>
      <description>Nice article by the lengendary Michael Abrash: Why virtual isn&amp;rsquo;t real to your brain. Before delving into technical detail, he shares some reflections on how sharing information probably helped him early in his carrier land a job at Microsoft, then Id, and more recently at Valve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an OpenERP v7 development environment on OSX using virtualenv</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/05/09/setting-up-openerp7-on-osx-using-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/05/09/setting-up-openerp7-on-osx-using-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>Nowdays I develop mostly on OSX using Python. I am particularly fond of using virtualenv and virtualenvwrapper for keeping separate environments for each project, so that the system&amp;rsquo;s Python distribution does not get contaminated with the project dependencies. (This also helps in having a clear set of library dependencies when deploying the project to a production server.)
Some days ago, while trying to set up a development environment1 for OpenERP v.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An implementation of Conway&#39;s Game of Life by a thirteen year old</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/03/23/an-implementation-of-conways-game-of-life-by-a-thirteen-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/03/23/an-implementation-of-conways-game-of-life-by-a-thirteen-year-old/</guid>
      <description>Thirteen years old Amy Mather explains how she got in programming, why she loves it, and her implementation of Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life for the Raspberry Pi.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing OSX&#39;s Open With duplicates</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/03/21/fixing-osx-open-with-duplicates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/03/21/fixing-osx-open-with-duplicates/</guid>
      <description>Getting rid of Open With duplicates, via Daring Fireball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown support in OSX QuickLook</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/01/12/markdown-support-in-osx-quicklook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/01/12/markdown-support-in-osx-quicklook/</guid>
      <description>If you work with Markdown files, this is an indispensable addition to OSX preview functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Ristretto</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/2013/01/07/blogging-with-ristretto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/2013/01/07/blogging-with-ristretto/</guid>
      <description>I have just finished the alpha version of Ristretto, a ‘baked’ blogging engine. That is, it&amp;rsquo;s an engine that reads posts written in Markdown and generates static html files.
Ristretto is loosely inspired on Marco Arment’s Second Crack. Some interesting references about why baked blogs are worth considering can be found in A plea for baked blogs, Blogging with Octropress, and Blogging with Second Crack.
Ristretto is written in Python. The alpha version of Ristretto is functional and can be used for daily blogging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
