<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on code.zoia.org</title>
    <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on code.zoia.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://code.zoia.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Wordpress on WPEngine</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/optimizing-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/optimizing-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Kevin Quirk&amp;rsquo;s post about Core Web Vitals and Wordpress, I spend some hours trying to improve the web vitals from my other site, which runs on Wordpress. (You can measure your site&amp;rsquo;s core vitals on web.dev.)
Some months ago I migrated that site from a self-hosted Linode instance to a managed solution on WPEngine. I&amp;rsquo;m essentially buying back time. A managed solution frees me from server admin duties, like making sure the latest Linux updates are installed, and PHP and its libraries up-to-date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symbiosis</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/emacs-gnu-symbiosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/emacs-gnu-symbiosis/</guid>
      <description>With emacs and gnus, one must serve a long penance, after which shit still doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite work but you&amp;rsquo;ve achieved a deep symbiosis with your editor/mailer and can tailor it to your very precise needs.
 Reddit</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henrik Lissner, Emacs Doom Creator on Doom Emacs</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/henrick-lissner-doom-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/henrick-lissner-doom-creator/</guid>
      <description>Jakub Zaiste interviews Henrik Lissner, Doom Emacs creator. njj
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Thunderbird to mu4e and back to Thunderbird</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/from-thunderbird-to-mu4e-and-back-to-thunderbird/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/from-thunderbird-to-mu4e-and-back-to-thunderbird/</guid>
      <description>I spent a couple of days configuring Emacs as an email client in my MacBook. There are lot of useful pages available on how to achieve this. The setup involves using a program like mbsync or offlineimap to create and maintain a local copy of your emails accounts on your computer, and installing and configuring an email client like notmuch or mu4e in Emacs. (Never could get OAUTH2 to work with mbsync so I had to settle for custom app passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doom Emacs, Hunspell, and MacOs</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/20210408-doom-emacs-hunspell-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/20210408-doom-emacs-hunspell-macos/</guid>
      <description>Doom Emacs uses spell-fu as the default highlighter for spellchecking. spell-fu can use several options like aspell, hunspell, enchant, etc. for the actual spellchecking. I prefer to use Hunspell.
The process to install and configure hunspell to work for Doom Emacs is simple:
 Use homebrew to install hunspell:   $ brew install hunspell  hunspell doesn&amp;rsquo;t install dictionaries. Download them from the aspell webpage and store them in ~/Library/Spelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove GRUB from MacOS boot partition</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/remove-grub-from-macos-boot-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/remove-grub-from-macos-boot-partition/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve got Linux on an external SSD drive which I can boot from my Macbook Pro using Command-D while powering up to select Linux as the boot drive.
The only glitch is that when installing Linux, by mistake I installed GRUB (Linux boot loader) on my Mac root partition. The easiest way to fix this is to boot the machine into repair mode using Command-R and reinstall MacOS. This won&amp;rsquo;t erase your data or applications, just reinstall the operating system and rewrite the boot partition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it Worth the Time?</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/is-it-worth-the-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/is-it-worth-the-time/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll copy this xkcd comic here so I can find when I fall into another Emacs org-mode time sink.
 Source: https://xkcd.com/1205/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanderson&#39;s Laws of Magic</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/sandersons-laws-of-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/sandersons-laws-of-magic/</guid>
      <description>Source: https://www.brandonsanderson.com/sandersons-first-law/
Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s First Law of Magic  An author&amp;rsquo;s ability to solve conflict with magic is DIRECTLY PROPORTIONAL to how well the reader understands said magic.
 Books with Soft Magic systems are books where magic is included in order to establish a sense of wonder and give the setting a fantastical feel. Really good writers of soft magic systems very rarely use their magic to solve problems in their books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 16.04 and Python 3.6&#43;</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/ubuntu-16-04-and-python-3-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/ubuntu-16-04-and-python-3-6/</guid>
      <description>I was recently upgrading a system from Django 2.2 to 3.2. Django 3.2 requires Python 3.6+. This system is running on a cloud instance of Ubuntu 16.04, which only supports Python up to 3.5.
Upgrading the server to Ubuntu 18.04 or 20.04 is out of the question. (Just the thought of someone typing `do-release-upgrade` in a production server makes me shiver&amp;hellip;) Also, the system is from a pre-docker era, so no luck there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Calibre with DeDRM tools on Linux to backup your Kindle library</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/calibre-drm-tools-and-kindle-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 12:52:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/calibre-drm-tools-and-kindle-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Kindle&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem lets you buy an ebook and begin reading seconds after purchasing it. However, as most of Amazon&amp;rsquo;s book are DRM-protected, you cannot make a backup of your library or convert your books´ format to read them on another platform. Companies come and go, and even if Amazon&amp;rsquo;s is here for the long run, it&amp;rsquo;s policies regarding how you can access the content your paid for may change in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Pelican to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/migrating-from-pelican-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/migrating-from-pelican-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated this blog from Pelican to Hugo.
This blog has always been a static/baked blog. Content is just a collection of html files which reside in a Linode instance. This allows me to use a very minimal server instance to host it. Dynamic content generators like Wordpress generate content by extracting the articles from a database and producing a webpage on the fly, they allow for more complex setups, but also have a higher footprint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a Windows 10 bootable USB on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2020/how-to-create-a-windows-10-bootable-usb-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2020/how-to-create-a-windows-10-bootable-usb-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>You don’t need Unetbootin, MacOS’ Boot Camp, or Rufus for Windows to create a Windows 10 USB bootable drive on a Mac to install Windows on a PC.
I needed to install Windows 10 in a new custom-build PC. I don’t have a single machine running Windows at home, so using Windows to create the bootable installer was out of the question. I tried most of the recommended methods, but after booting from the USB drive and partitioning the disk of the new machine, the Windows installer always complained that it couldn’t find some files it needed for the installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network problems</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2020/network-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2020/network-problems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this happen even at home&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guido van Rossum on Maintainable Code and other things</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2019/guido-van-rossum-maintainable-code-and-other-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2019/guido-van-rossum-maintainable-code-and-other-things/</guid>
      <description>I love Python, so I maybe somewhat biassed about this article on Dropbox’s Blog: Thank You, Guido</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to Public Wifi in MacOS Catalina</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2019/connecting-to-public-wifi-in-macos-catalina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2019/connecting-to-public-wifi-in-macos-catalina/</guid>
      <description>After upgrading to MacOS Catalina, I could no longer connect to open WiFI networks, specifically hotel networks and coffee shops. Previously, when connecting to one of these networks, a dialog would appear to ask for confirmation, a username/password combination, etc. No longer with Catalina.
After some extensive searching on the internet, the solution I found is launching the Captive Network Assistant manually. I wrote a small bash script to launch it from the command line on a terminal window:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Cobra and the worldwide ATM hacks</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2018/hidden-cobra-and-the-worldwide-atm-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2018/hidden-cobra-and-the-worldwide-atm-hacks/</guid>
      <description>US-CERT on the August/September 2018 ATM hacks which affected several nations:
 (&amp;hellip;) all of the compromised switch application servers were running unsupported IBM Advanced Interactive eXecutive (AIX) operating system versions beyond the end of their service pack support dates;
 This is the typical example of short-term thinking. Someone/some comittee decides not to spend on a supported version of a particular software, but don&amp;rsquo;t consider what the downside could be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infocom Text Games on MacOs</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2017/infocom-games-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2017/infocom-games-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>I played lot of Infocom text games when I was a kid. I remember drawing maps by hand, and inmersing myself in the stories. (There was no internet, so cheats came only from friends.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Whatsapp Client Blues</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2017/python-whatsapp-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2017/python-whatsapp-blues/</guid>
      <description>I had the idea to code a simple script in Python that would notify of the day&amp;rsquo;s birthdays to a Whatsapp number or a Whatsapp group.
WhatsApp has no public API (that I&amp;rsquo;m aware of&amp;hellip;) I spent some time with YowSup, which didn&amp;rsquo;t work with the examples of their own page. After applying some changes suggested in the YowSup forums, I was able to register my cel number and obtain a password for the account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Your Parrot AR Drone Blades (Propellers)</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2017/replacing-parrot-ar-drone-propeller-blades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2017/replacing-parrot-ar-drone-propeller-blades/</guid>
      <description>The Parrot AR Drone has a total of four blades (or propellers&amp;hellip;). Note that not all blades are equal. Each blade has a letter printed near the shaft hole. Two blades are labeled &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo;, and the other two are labeled &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;.
While replacing the blades is pretty straightforward, the critical step is getting the blades in the right order. Otherwise, your drone won&amp;rsquo;t take off. (It will roll over one side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Pelican to Wordpress</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2016/11/from-pelican-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2016/11/from-pelican-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated my main blog from Pelican to Wordpress. (Pelican is a static blog generator.)
The main reason for changing is that I to make some changes in my webpage layout, or add some feature like a landing page, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to make (program) all the changes myself.
Using Wordpress will add complexity to my publishing workflow, but things like implementing landing pages and writing custom page archives can be quickly done in Wordpress by using the appropriate plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shawn Blanc interviews John Gruber</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2016/02/shawn-blanc-interviews-john-gruber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2016/02/shawn-blanc-interviews-john-gruber/</guid>
      <description>This is interview is from 2008, by I&amp;rsquo;ve just re-read it and thought it was worth linking for my future reference: John Gruber: A Mix of the Technical, the Artful, the Thoughtful, and the Absurd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is GIT</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/11/this-is-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/11/this-is-git/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Code?</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/06/what-is-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/06/what-is-code/</guid>
      <description>Excellent long article by Paul Ford: What is Code?.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brandon Sanderson Creative Writing 2013</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/06/creative-writing-brandon-sanderson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/06/creative-writing-brandon-sanderson/</guid>
      <description>I recently found this [great] 2013 course on Creative Writing by Brandon Sanderson (!!). I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here for future reference.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify:  move code into database functions</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/05/simplify-move-code-into-database-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/05/simplify-move-code-into-database-functions/</guid>
      <description>Interesting article by Derek Sivers. What if the code for some basic operations were coded in the database itself, instead of in the server-side or client-side layer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Hacker?</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/02/what-is-a-hacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2015/02/what-is-a-hacker/</guid>
      <description>Steven Levy: What is a Hacker?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Parallel between Chess and Programming</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/11/the-parallel-between-chess-and-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/11/the-parallel-between-chess-and-programming/</guid>
      <description>I found this quote I wrote down some time ago from an interview with Victoria Livschitz, serial entrepreneur, a founder of Grid Dynamics and more recently, a technology start-up Qubell1.
 Chess, like any other complex intellectual activity, involves a combination of knowledge, creative vision, and technique. Good chess players are able to acquire and store a lot of information &amp;ndash; classic and trendy opening systems, standard endgame positions, novelties specific to their repertoire, and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Markdown and how to fork a project</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/09/on-markdown-and-how-to-fork-a-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/09/on-markdown-and-how-to-fork-a-project/</guid>
      <description>Markdown and its syntax specification were developed by John Gruber as a text-to-HTML conversion tool for webwriters. Over the years, it has been widely adopted by sites likes GitHub and StackExchange. Most programming languages have some kind of Markdown library available, always developed not by Gruber but by some third party.
The syntax for Markdown hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in years. Different implementations implement Markdown different&amp;hellip; and output different HTML code for the same markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marco Arment on Overcast</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/08/marco-arment-on-overcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/08/marco-arment-on-overcast/</guid>
      <description>Just finished listening to Episode 43 of Debug, where Guy English and Rene Ritchie interview Marco Arment about the recent launch of Overcast, his podcasting app for iPhone.
The episode is great. It is around three hours long but worth the time if you are interested in iOS development and the app ecosystem. Marco explains some of the problems he found while implementing the app and how he solved them, and his product design decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>glFlush(); goto Metal;</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/06/glflush-goto-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/06/glflush-goto-metal/</guid>
      <description>Nice piece from Guy English about Metal, Apple&amp;rsquo;s new API for lower level access to the GPU than is afforded by OpenGL ES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t be afraid to take risks</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/06/dont-be-afraid-to-take-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/06/dont-be-afraid-to-take-risks/</guid>
      <description>A quote from _why about experimenting and taking risks, before his disapparition.
 I do not write tests for my code. I do not write very many comments. I change styles very frequently. And most of all, I shun the predominant styles of coding, because that would go against the very essence of experimentation. In short: all I do is muck around.
  So, my way of measuring a great programmer is different from some prevailing thought on the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infocom&#39;s The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy original ad</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/06/infocoms-the-hitchhiker-guide-to-the-galaxy-original-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/06/infocoms-the-hitchhiker-guide-to-the-galaxy-original-ad/</guid>
      <description>I spend hours playing this game&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time interviews Jonathan Ive</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/05/time-interviews-johnny-ive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/05/time-interviews-johnny-ive/</guid>
      <description>Interviews to Apple&amp;rsquo;s Senior VP of Design are unfrequent. Worth reading.
 Objects and their manufacture are inseparable. You understand a product if you understand how it’s made. I want to know what things are for, how they work, what they can or should be made of, before I even begin to think what they should look like. More and more people do. There is a resurgence of the idea of craft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Heartbleed works, by xkcd</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/how-the-heartbleed-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/how-the-heartbleed-works/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science is about what is. Engineering is about what can be</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/science-is-about-what-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/science-is-about-what-is/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Science is about what is. Engineering is about what CAN be.&amp;rdquo; (via PhD Comics)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug 31:  Miguel de Icaza on Mono</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/miguel-de-icaza-on-mono/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/miguel-de-icaza-on-mono/</guid>
      <description>Guy English and Rene Ritchie interview Miguel de Icaza in Episode 31 of Debug. I liked the interview very much, specially from minute 20 on when Miguel talks about functionality and implementation details of the Mono runtime, async calls, garbage collection&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write the code. Change the world (WWDC 2014)</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/write-the-code-change-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/write-the-code-change-the-world/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indispensable read for app developers</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/indispensable-read-for-app-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/04/indispensable-read-for-app-developers/</guid>
      <description>Three posts by Marco Arment that you should read if you are an app developer: Web Hosting for App Developers, What Did I Just Learn?, and Wrong about home-hosting?.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reid Hoffman and Matt Mullenweg in LinkedIn Speaker Series</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/reid-hoffman-and-matt-mullenweg-in-linkedin-speaker-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/reid-hoffman-and-matt-mullenweg-in-linkedin-speaker-series/</guid>
      <description>Matt Mullenweg (co-founder of WordPress and CEO of Automattic) and Reid Hoffman (LinkedIn co-founder) share their thoughts about the future of online publishing (among other things).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/simplicity-is-the-ultimate-sophistication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/simplicity-is-the-ultimate-sophistication/</guid>
      <description>Just finished watching Simple Made Easy, a talk by Rich Hickey, creator of Clojure, at The Strange Loop 2011 conference. Recommended (1 hour).
 Simple has a core meaning, an understanding of which is critical to developing robust and flexible software. We should be simplifying the problem domain, and creating solutions by composing simple parts. Instead, we endure complexity, and pride ourselves in our ability to manage it. We can do better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen King at UMass Lowell</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/stephen-king-at-umass-lowell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/stephen-king-at-umass-lowell/</guid>
      <description>A one hour long interview with Stephen King.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Making of Templar</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/book-the-making-of-templar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/book-the-making-of-templar/</guid>
      <description>I somehow missed The Making of Templar, a free ebook by Jordan Mechner, LeUyen Pham, and Alex Puvilland.
Jordan Mechner is best known as the creator of great games like Karateka (1984), Prince of Persia (1989), The Last Express (1997)&amp;hellip; Most of these games are now available for modern platforms like iOS and Android.
You can download the free ebook from Jordan Mechner&amp;rsquo;s page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why people are scared of free software</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/why-people-are-scared-of-free-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/why-people-are-scared-of-free-software/</guid>
      <description>Matt Mullenweg on why people are scared of free software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCloud Keychain Security</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/icloud-keychain-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/icloud-keychain-security/</guid>
      <description>Apple has released an update to its iOS Security whitepaper. Rich Mogull makes a good summary of the whitepaper, and explains why he thinks Apple has provided a way to make it impossible for a third party to obtain your iCloud Keychain passwords.
Worth reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is a Lightning cable required for CarPlay</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/lightning-cable-required-for-carplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/03/lightning-cable-required-for-carplay/</guid>
      <description>Wondering why CarPlay requires your iPhone to be conected via a Lightning cable? Engadget gives a hint.
 the CarPlay connection is based on the H.264 video protocol, and sends user input from the touchscreen back to your iDevice
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Pelican, Dropbox, and automatic blog publishing</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/02/pelican-dropbox-automatic-blog-regeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/02/pelican-dropbox-automatic-blog-regeneration/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will explain how I set up Pelican on a Linux (Ubuntu) server to mantain multiple blogs, using Dropbox for file synchronization, watcher to detect changes in the blog&amp;rsquo;s content and regenerate it , and Apache to serve the resulting files.
 The blogs&amp;rsquo;s content will reside in a shared Dropbox folder. This is where posts are written in Markdown format (or .rst if you prefer). Pelican template (themes) files will also reside in this Dropbox folder, so you can modifiy your blog&amp;rsquo;s theme if needed without logging into your web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog migrated to Pelican</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/02/blog-migrated-to-pelican/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2014/02/blog-migrated-to-pelican/</guid>
      <description>A year ago I started developing a static blogging engine called Ristretto. It was written in Python, used markdown files as input, Jinja2 for templating, and generated static html files on my web server. Some weeks later, I migrated my main blog (zoia.org) and this blog from Wordpress to my new blogging platform.
Compared to writing in Wordpress, I enjoyed the new platform a lot. Over 2013 I kept adding functionality to Ristretto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cubr, a Rubik&#39;s cube solver written in Python</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/09/27/cubr-a-rubiks-cube-solver-written-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/09/27/cubr-a-rubiks-cube-solver-written-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Cubr is a program by Chris Baker. You mix up a Rubik&amp;rsquo;s cube, show it to your computer&amp;rsquo;s webcam, and magically the cube begins to solve itself.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why virtual isn&#39;t real to your brain</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/06/04/why-virtual-isnt-real-to-your-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/06/04/why-virtual-isnt-real-to-your-brain/</guid>
      <description>Nice article by the lengendary Michael Abrash: Why virtual isn&amp;rsquo;t real to your brain. Before delving into technical detail, he shares some reflections on how sharing information probably helped him early in his carrier land a job at Microsoft, then Id, and more recently at Valve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up an OpenERP v7 development environment on OSX using virtualenv</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/05/09/setting-up-openerp7-on-osx-using-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/05/09/setting-up-openerp7-on-osx-using-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>Nowdays I develop mostly on OSX using Python. I am particularly fond of using virtualenv and virtualenvwrapper for keeping separate environments for each project, so that the system&amp;rsquo;s Python distribution does not get contaminated with the project dependencies. (This also helps in having a clear set of library dependencies when deploying the project to a production server.)
Some days ago, while trying to set up a development environment1 for OpenERP v.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An implementation of Conway&#39;s Game of Life by a thirteen year old</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/03/23/an-implementation-of-conways-game-of-life-by-a-thirteen-year-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/03/23/an-implementation-of-conways-game-of-life-by-a-thirteen-year-old/</guid>
      <description>Thirteen years old Amy Mather explains how she got in programming, why she loves it, and her implementation of Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life for the Raspberry Pi.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing OSX&#39;s Open With duplicates</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/03/21/fixing-osx-open-with-duplicates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/03/21/fixing-osx-open-with-duplicates/</guid>
      <description>Getting rid of Open With duplicates, via Daring Fireball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown support in OSX QuickLook</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/01/12/markdown-support-in-osx-quicklook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/01/12/markdown-support-in-osx-quicklook/</guid>
      <description>If you work with Markdown files, this is an indispensable addition to OSX preview functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Ristretto</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/01/07/blogging-with-ristretto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2013/01/07/blogging-with-ristretto/</guid>
      <description>I have just finished the alpha version of Ristretto, a ‘baked’ blogging engine. That is, it&amp;rsquo;s an engine that reads posts written in Markdown and generates static html files.
Ristretto is loosely inspired on Marco Arment’s Second Crack. Some interesting references about why baked blogs are worth considering can be found in A plea for baked blogs, Blogging with Octropress, and Blogging with Second Crack.
Ristretto is written in Python. The alpha version of Ristretto is functional and can be used for daily blogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog publishing from Dropbox</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2012/12/14/blog-publishing-from-dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2012/12/14/blog-publishing-from-dropbox/</guid>
      <description>The geek inside me longs for something like http://scriptogr.am, a solution where you publish a new post just by creating a Markdown file in a folder on your Dropbox account. Your post gets automagically coverted to static HTML and published on your site.
The geek inside me longs for writing some code to accomplish the same&amp;hellip;
Wordpress is a great platform, and I use it for several blogs. But for most of my needs I could use a simpler solution that did not require a ton of plugins to accomplish simple tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparent ssh tunnel for Mac and PC</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2012/12/14/transparent-ssh-tunnel-for-mac-and-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2012/12/14/transparent-ssh-tunnel-for-mac-and-pc/</guid>
      <description>I use Sidestep on OSX to build an encrypted connection to a remote server of my own through when connecting to the Internet on public WiFi networks. But the latest version of SideStep does not work reliably with Mountain Lion.
TunnelBear offers an alternative, and its free for casual use (up to 500MB monthly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Templatic&#39;s Private Lawyer text-being-truncated-on-slider bug</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2012/06/06/fix-templatics-private-lawyer-text-being-truncated-on-slider-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2012/06/06/fix-templatics-private-lawyer-text-being-truncated-on-slider-bug/</guid>
      <description>I was having problems with the Coda Slider in the Private Lawyer Wordpress Theme by Templatic. (The slider is called the T Anything Slider widget by the theme.) Text was being truncated even when the text length was less than the number of characters specified on the widget settings.
A small modification to the bm_better_excerpt function in wp-content/themes/PrivateLaweyer/library/functions/custom_functions.php solves the problem.
File: wp-content/themes/PrivateLaweyer/library/functions/custom_functions.php
&amp;lt;?php // Excerpt length function bm_better_excerpt($length, $ellipsis) { $text = get_the_content(); // // fix weird bug that caused substr to chop // text even if $length was greater than string length if (strlen($text) &amp;gt; $length) { $text = strip_tags($text); $text = substr($text, 0, $length); $text = substr($text, 0, strrpos($text, &amp;#34; &amp;#34;)); $text = $text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Textmate 2.0 alpha</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/12/15/textmate-2-0-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/12/15/textmate-2-0-alpha/</guid>
      <description>Finally. If you have a licensed copy of Textmate 1.5, grab your copy here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Carmack on rigorous code analysis</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/08/25/john-carmack-on-rigorous-code-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/08/25/john-carmack-on-rigorous-code-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Gamasutra interviews John Carmack, creator of Doom.
 One of the humbling things that you find is that, no matter how good of a programmer you are, you write code, and you make stupid mistakes. And I am getting to be a huge proponent of really, really rigorous code analysis, because I have been going through pioneering these things, just squeegeeing through our code base, and every single programmer &amp;ndash; from our best to our worst &amp;ndash; they all make stupid mistakes, and they are unavoidable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using TextMate and Python&#39;s virtualenv</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/05/25/using-textmate-and-python-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/05/25/using-textmate-and-python-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>TextMate is a great text editor for MacOs. But the default Python bundle does not recognize Python&amp;rsquo;s virtual environments (virtualenv), which is rather annoying.
No need to modify your Textmate bundle. This can be solved by declaring a project-specific shell variable named TM_PYTHON and assigning your virtualenv&amp;rsquo;s custom python&amp;rsquo;s path to it:
 In TextMate, create a new project for your python program Open the Project Drawer Window (View/Open Project Drawer) Make sure no file is selected in the drawer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Programming 101</title>
      <link>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/04/15/java-programming-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://code.zoia.org/post/2011/04/15/java-programming-101/</guid>
      <description>Releyendo unos posts antiguos de otro blog, encontré unos apuntes que escribí el 2006 para complementar las clases de Programación Java que dicté en la Facultad de Ingeniería de la Universidad de Piura en Lima. Los vuelvo a publicar por si sirven a otros.
Los apuntes están publicados bajo una licencia Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 2.5. Se pueden crear trabajos derivados, copiar, compartir, etc., mientras se respete esa licencia. Si alguno quiere los archivos originales para modificarlos, se los puedo enviar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
